DOUGLAS MAFFEI, P.E.

32 Appletree Lane | Norwalk, CT 06850 | 203-814-2281 | dcmaffei@aol.com

QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY

Over 30 years of heavy civil construction experience which has included the construction of various deep foundations, concrete and steel structures, bridge, railroad, highway, airport, and marine work of a highly complex nature throughout the northeast US. Extensive knowledge of construction methods, equipment, controls, quality, and safety, along with an engineering background allowing to progress in positions of increasing responsibility. Continually strive for complete client satisfaction while maximizing commercial potential.

EXPERIENCE

Mount Construction Berlin, NJ 2021 to August, 2022

Vice President, Marine Division and Major Projects

Hired to strengthen the Mount senior management team by helping grow the company, and in particular, expanding the marine division. This is accomplished by assisting in the estimating of larger more complex projects in wider geographic markets, and by strengthening existing client relationships and developing new ones. Additional focus is on applying large-company standard operating procedures to Mount existing management practices to maximize efficiency, safety, quality, and profitability. Provide management guidance to field teams on current projects with cost and schedule challenges.

Role also includes the purchase of marine and other support equipment needed to facilitate future grow as well as support current projects. Effort is spent on identifying what physical and human resources are required to enable and maintain company expansion. Act as project manager on current bridge repair contracts. Mentor younger construction professionals on career path decisions.

Walsh Construction Little Falls, NJ 2019 - 2020

Senior Project Manager

PANYNJ Project 164.020, Reconstruction of Runway 13L-31R at John F. Kennedy Airport, \$152M Joint Venture with Grace Industries. Served as JV Project Manager.

Led the team in all aspects on this project with an extremely aggressive, single-construction season schedule. Negotiated PA change orders to accelerate the completion of two milestone stages to satisfy airline tenant demands to turn over 4 taxiways earlier.

In charge of both field and office operations. Supervised 20 person management staff of managers, engineers, superintendents, and accountants. Responsible for all financial obligations, profit/loss, weekly and monthly cost & revenue forecasts, change order management, material, subcontractors, and equipment procurement. Fully responsible for safety.

Work was performed with 3-shifts, 7 days/week. Craft work force peaked at 300. Scope included the full reconstruction of over 8,000' of new 200' wide concrete runway and 12 asphalt pavement taxiways, with over 1,500 new aeronautical lights. Schedule required the assembly and operation of two on-site mobile concrete batch plants, producing up to 3,500 CY/day, a total of 120,000 CY.

Senior Project Manager

2020

NYCTA Project C-34838, Sandy Repairs and Flood Mitigation at the 207th Street Transit Railyard in Manhattan, \$368M

This project repairs the damage caused by Hurricane Sandy and will protect the facility against future events. Scope includes the replacement of 22 yard tracks, erection of two relay buildings, replacement of power feeders & signals, a 1,535' long flood wall adjacent to the Harlem River. In direct charge of all deep foundation works required for the new steel flood gates.

Skanska, Underpinning and Foundation

Maspeth, NY

2006 - 2018

Project Executive

In direct charge of construction operations of deep foundation projects. This included activities such as production planning, procurement of both temporary and permanent material and tooling, selection of equipment and manpower, and execution of the day-to-day operations. Worked closely with the client project representatives, from bid award through project completion. Responsible for the compliance with contract plans and specifications, including all corporate safety, health, and environmental regulations. Managed multiple projects concurrently.

Fully responsible for profit and loss on all projects. Developed and pursued change orders for extra work, scope changes, and Differing Site Conditions with project clients. Developed new and improved existing company-wide systems and procedures such as change order tracking, contracts review, material procurement, job cost & revenue management, and equipment management. Focused on the development of employees within the organization.

Projects included caissons, secant pile walls, drilled shafts, mini-piles, H-pile, sheet pile, auger cast, and rock anchor works throughout the northeast region. Notable projects are:

- * LaGuardia Airport Expansion
- * World Trade Center Projects
- * Eastside Access in Sunnyside Yards
- * Moynihan/Farley Station

- * Manahawkin Bridge, NJ
- * Fore River Bridge, MA
- * New Yankee Stadium
- * Eleventh Street Washington, DC

Geothermal Energy Initiative

Worked to introduce *Energy Piles* to the US market. This involved collaboration with Skanska UK, Skanska US, and engineering design firms.

Balfour Beatty Construction

Bridgeport, CT

2003 - 2006

Project Manager

CDOT Project - Reconstruction of I-95 in Bridgeport: \$120M, highly complex bridge and highway replacement project with 12 retaining walls and 7 bridges, with its largest being 5' and 8' diameter drilled shafts and H-piles.

Managed 19 person staff of engineers, superintendents, surveyors, and administrators, and a craft workforce of up to 85 employees. Responsible for the overall construction of the project through completion by managing field construction operations, subcontractor selection & coordination and equipment oversight. Fully responsible for profit and loss. Worked on the development and pursuit of a \$21M Acceleration Claim against the CDOT

through the formal Mediation process.

Project Engineer

1997 - 2003

Supervised 7 person engineering staff, consisting of schedule, cost, and structural engineers, field engineer, and surveyors. Responsible for the planning and execution of procedures for all work activities, as well as directed critical field activities, examples included concrete and steel demolition, concrete forming and pouring, support of excavation, and post tensioning. Work included the selection and coordination of outside engineering consultants and subcontractors and specialized equipment. Coordinated shop drawings, working drawings, and materials testing requirements.

New England Railroad Construction

Bridgeport, CT

1989 - 1997

Project Engineer

Designed various construction procedures including concrete pouring, excavation, shoring, and demolition for bridges and other structures. Responsible for compliance with plans and specifications during all phases of construction. Acted as liaison with project owners. Projects included bridge, road, site, storm, sanitary sewer, and railroad contracts throughout the northeast US. Project owners included CDOT, MTA, MBTA, and SEPTA.

Barden Corp.

Danbury, CT

1987 - 1989

Mechanical Engineer

Responsible for the design and fabrication of machine tooling. Served as technical support to production personnel. Developed labor and material saving techniques and researched new methods to improve product quality.

EDUCATION

University of New Haven

New Haven, CT 2000

M.S., Environmental Engineering (Civil Concentration)

University of Dayton

Dayton, OH

1987

B.S., Mechanical Engineering Technology

University of New Haven

New Haven, CT

1993

A.S., Civil Engineering

REGISTRATION

Professional Engineer, State of Connecticut

PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

Seminars in:

- * Fundamentals of Finance & Accounting for Non-Financial Managers
- * Construction Schedule Delay Claims
- * Contractual Risk Awareness and Mitigation
- * Shifting or Accepting the Risk of Differing Site Conditions in Construction Contracts
- * Resolution to Inefficiency Claims on Differing Site Conditions